皆さんは　よく眠れているでしょうか
明日か
まさに全校をあげてって感じだね
絶対うまく回らなきゃ
ええと　クイズ研は一時からっと
将棋トーナメントか　ちょっと自信ないな
料理コンテストは用チェックだよね
いよいよ明日か
This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance to real persons, groups or events is purely coincidental.
I wonder if the others are sleeping all right.
明日か
どうか　明日からの三日間
私たちに幸運がありますように
あの山を乗り越えられますように
Tomorrow, huh?
さあ　文化祭です
@ 湮·Molly／小然·酸菜／喵儿·小冷／时末·竭力而为
KamiGami
This'll really liven up the whole school.
複雑に構えた今日が 息を呑んで澄ましてる
It's gotta work out well.
Let's see, the quizzes start at one...
身に覚えあるだろう 君はどうしたい
I'm not so sure about the shogi tournament.
何もなかったそぶりで  かばう痛みはもう
But I definitely need to check out the cooking contest.
It's finally tomorrow!
心強いくらいに 急かすんだ
掴んでこぼして 不完全な僕たちが
光って見えない 未来の自分を創れるなら
Tomorrow, huh?
1 day left until the Kan'ya fair
目覚めるまま走れ 蜃気楼を追い越して
変わりたいまま走れ 自由な違和感で
届きそうな輝きと今を選んでいこう
May we advance through these three days with good fortune!
May we have the determination to conquer that mountain!
飛びたつ手を知らない
深い 浅い 呼吸を重ねて
Hyouka
It's the culture fair!
A Huge Pile of the Stuff
无限堆积的那个
おはよう
Morning!
ああ　早いな　姉貴
Hey! You're up early, Sis.
You've got the culture fair today, right?
あんた文化祭よね
そうだ
Yeah.
I get the feeling you might run into a few issues.
何かトラブルあったんじゃない
何で分かる
Where did you get that feeling?
Just a hunch.
何となく
それに　古典部の文化祭は
It's a Classics Club tradition to run into trouble during the culture fair.
トラブルなしには終わらないのが伝統だからね
厄介な伝統を残すな
I could do without a tradition that's gonna cause me trouble.
それなら　お守りの一つでもくれよ　先輩
The least you could do is give me a good-luck charm, Ms. Senio—
はい
There. You can have that.
じゃ　それやる
Am I supposed to say thanks?
ありがとうと言えばいいのか
By the way, it's out of ink and the tip is broken.
ああ　ちなみに
インク切れてて　ペン先割れてるから
ゴミを寄こすな　ゴミを
I don't recall becoming a trash can.
あんた遅刻するよ
You'll be late.
分かってるよ
I know.
暇だったら様子見に行くからね
I'll drop by if I feel bored enough!
Please don't!
いや　来るな
It's the culture fair, Houtarou!
文化祭だよ　奉太郎
そうらしいな
It would seem so.
相変わらずだね　奉太郎は
You never change, do you?
お前は楽しそうだな
And you still seem to be enjoying yourself.
そりゃそうだよ
Of course I am!
The culture fair is the one great constant of all club traditions!
部活の伝統　神山高校の文化祭だからね
Look, isn't that Mayaka?
あれ　摩耶花じゃないか
She's probably dressed up for the Manga Lab.
たぶん漫研の衣装だね
From the looks of it, they're also scheduled to work at the festival.
摩耶花たちも外見からお祭りシフトなんだ
Did you have something on your mind as well?
お前も何か考えてるのか
僕は手芸部員でもあるからね
I'm in the Handicraft Club, after all.
Let me say hi.
ちょっとちょっかい出してくる
Hey, Mayaka.
よ　摩耶花　おはよう
Good morning.
おはよう
似合ってるよ　その服
Those clothes look good on you.
Stop that.
止めてよ
And who are you cosp—
で　それ何のコスプ
Don't use words like that in front of normal people.
堅気さんの前でその用語は使わないで
Roger.
了解
Then, who are you dressed as?
じゃ　それ何の装い
フロル
Frol.
フロル？フロル·ベリチェリ　フロル？
Frol? Frolbericheri Frol?
Yeah.
うん　後で手袋もする
I'll put on gloves later.
Nice!
その荷物　何
What's in your bag?
This and that.
ちょっとね
That sounds suspicious.
何か怪しい
So are you gonna be at the Manga Lab the whole time?
摩耶花はずっと漫研だっけ
Yeah.
うん　売り子を引き受けちゃったから　こんな時なのに
I ended up having to work at the counter.
Today, of all days!
ま　その件はあまり考えないことだね
Don't worry about stuff like that.
起きたことは仕方がない
You can't do anything about the past.
This is it! The culture fair!
これぞ文化祭だ
Yeah.
うん
I heard a lot about it, but this exceeds all my expectations!
聞いてはいたけど　想像以上だよ
Whoa, look at this!
何だこれ　なかなかよく出来てるよ
It's so well done!
Yeah.
本当だ
It's pretty lively.
賑やかだ
A little too lively.
賑やか過ぎる
You're done?
ね　終わった
Yeah, I'm done.
うん　終わったよ
すごいね
Amazing.
Okay, let's get this done!
よーし　遣らかすぞ
じゃ　僕は一旦ここで
I'll part with you here for now.
手芸部か
Going sewing?
Just for a bit.
ちょっとね
I'll be right there!
でも　すぐ行くから
It's awfully quiet.
静かだな
そうね
Yeah.
あんまりこだわるな
Get over it.
お前が気にし続けると
If you keep dwelling on that,
you'll get Chitanda fixated on it as well as Satoshi.
里志はともかく　千反田まで気にせざるをえなくなる
I know.
分かってるわよ
Classics Club Anthology
"Hyouka" issue #46
On sale
Good morning, Oreki, Mayaka.
おはようございます　折木さん　摩耶花さん
おはよう　ちーちゃん
Morning, Chi.
いよいよですね
The time is here!
It is.
そうだな
Let's give it our best shot!
頑張りましょう
Yeah.
ああ
頑張ってどうにかなるものなのか
Though will that even help in this case?
つまりですね　頑張れば何とかなる保障はありませんが
The thing is,
there's no guarantee it'll work out even if we try our hardest,
but I can guarantee it won't work out unless we put effort into it!
頑張らなければ　なんともならないことは保障できます
ごもっともで
If you say so.
Okay, I guess I will buy some!
やっぱり私が買うわ
That's not why I said that!
そんなつもりで言ったんじゃないんです
But I'm the one who ordered them...
でも　発注したのは私だから
How many did we plan on originally?
もともとの予定は何部だった
Thirty.
三十部よ
And how many have we got now?
実際に届いたのが
Two hundred.
二百部です
Galaxy!
ギャラクシー
Oh no, my Saturn!
ああ　僕のサターンが
I see you made it.
やっと来たか
Good morning, Fukube.
おはようございます　福部さん
Sorry to keep you waiting.
お待たせしちゃった
It's okay. We haven't started yet.
大丈夫です　まだ始めてませんから
皆　本当にごめん
Guys, I'm so sorry!
It's my fault for not double-checking our order with the printing company.
私が印刷場からのメールを確認しなかったばかりに
Everyone makes mistakes.
失敗のない人なんていないさ
その格好で言うか
You're saying that in those clothes?
一人で背負い込むことないよ
You shouldn't take all the blame upon yourself.
We're friends, aren't we?
僕たち仲間だろう
その格好で言うか
You're saying that in those clothes?
その通りです
That's true!
私も部長として確認するべきでした
As club president, it was my responsibility to check it too.
I just handed over the manuscript and didn't pay any further attention.
まあ　俺も原稿渡してそれっきりだったからな
古典部全員の責任だろう
It's our collective responsibility as members of the Classics Club.
Yes! I agree!
はい　そう思います
分かった
Okay. I get it.
ようやく分かってくれたようだね
You finally got it.
Stop saying stuff like that in those clothes!
だからその格好で言うか
それでは　開会式まで時間がありません
We have no time until the opening ceremony.
Does anyone have any idea how we could sell most of these?
どうすれば一番たくさん売ることができるか
何かいい考えはないでしょうか
How much does one cost?
一冊いくらだった
200 yen.
二百円です
That's quite cheap.
十分安いほうだ
The problem is the Classics Club isn't well-known
問題は古典部のネームバリューの無さと
and we're cursed with a bad location.
立地条件の悪さだね
Yeah.
So first off we need to get the word out
つまり　知名度のアップと
and find a better place from which to sell.
もっといい場所に売り場を作るのが大前提だろうな
Are we going to set up a new stall?
ほかに売り場を作るですか
私どうやってここまでお客様を連れてくるかってことばかり考えてました
I've been trying to think of ways to lure customers here all this time!
This will turn the tables on them, Oreki!
発想の逆転ですね　折木さん
I wouldn't really go that far.
いや　逆転ってほどのものじゃ
But would we get permission to do that at this point?
でも　当日になって　そんなこと許可下りるかな
Well...
それは
You're in the council, so tell us.
どうなんだ　総務委員
そういう特権が認められるかどうかなんだけど
It'd have to be a special exception,
so you'd need to ask the Student Council president
内の委員長か　生徒会長辺りに直接ねじ込んでみるとか
or our General Affairs president directly.
総務委員長って誰だ
Who's handling General Affairs at the moment?
You could at least look at the guide, Houtarou.
しおりぐらい見ておいてくれよ　奉太郎
Look, here.
ほら　ここ
President:
Tanabe Jirou
First time I've seen that name.
初めて見た
もう　この仕掛けには気付いてもらいたかったね
I hoped you'd notice my little trick.
それがどうした
Your what?
What do you think? Subtle, huh?
どう　目立ってない
ほら　各部紹介のラストに古典部が来てるだろう
Just look at the end of the club list, and here's the Classics Club.
I pulled a few strings to get it in there.
僕が無理いってここに入れてもらったんだよ
This booklet was edited by those of us at General Affairs.
編集は総務委員会だからね
すごいですね
That's amazing!
More like you're abusing your authority.
職権濫用だろう
Don't worry yourself.
ま　いいじゃない
If you want to talk to the president, go to the meeting room.
委員長に会いたかったら会議室で行ってみなよ
Can't you ask him for us?
お前から頼めないのか
Well, I could.
まあ　その手もあるけどね
でも　あんまり交渉には自信がないんだ
But I'm not really the diplomatic type.
Really?
そうなんですか
Chitanda, you should go talk to him.
千反田さんから話を持ちかけて
僕が横から口添えする形でどうかな
I'll be there to offer moral support.
Please help us!
よろしくどうぞ
I get it. Let's do it.
分かりました　それで行きましょう
She doesn't seem all that enthusiastic about this.
あんまり乗り気じゃなさそうだな
そう　それより　僕が宣伝に尽くしたいね
But more importantly, I'll promote our club myself!
So that's why you're dressed like that?
それでその格好か
That's one reason.
これはその一つだよ
I have a special move!
もっと秘策があるんだ
So you have a new idea we can use?
何かいい方法があるんですか
We should enter the culture fair's events and contests under the club's name!
この文化祭で開催されるコンテストやイベントに
古典部の名前で出場するんだ
If we play our cards right, our club could gain fame and fortune!
そこで好成績を収めれば　古典部の名も上がるって寸法だよ
You're just in this to have fun, aren't you?
お前が楽しみたいだけだろう
それはいい考えですね
That's a wonderful idea!
Right?
でしょう
Yeah!
はい　さすが福部さんです
You're amazing, Fukube!
Wait a moment.
Just leave it to me!
いや　待ってよ
任せてくれよ
That's a good idea. Let's make that our main approach.
それはいい考えだ　方針は決まったな
千反田が売り場拡張の交渉で
Chitanda should negotiate for a better selling spot.
Satoshi's in charge of promotion.
里志が宣伝する
Let's stick to that for now.
取りあえず　それで行きましょう
でも　折木さんは
But... what about you, Oreki?
俺は
I'll...
Yes?
はい
...hold the fort.
店番する
まあ　誰かはいないとね
Well, someone does have to stay here.
That's right.
そうですね
Let's get going then.
The opening ceremony's about to start.
じゃ　そろそろ行こうよ
開会式の点呼始まっちゃう
Yeah.
はい
Well then,
では　今の通りの分担で行きたいと思います
let's stick to the plan,
and sell as many as we can!
何とか一部でも多く売りましょう
The goal is to sell all 200 copies of Hyouka!
目標は　氷菓　二百部の　完売です
Let's go!
せーの
Hey-hey-ho!
...Ho.
秋分
阴阳相半也
Autumn Equinox
When light and dark are in balance.
Hyouka
クイズ研からどう
ね
兎
本当すごいよね
って感じ
Without further ado,
唯今より　第54回 カンヤ祭を　開催します
the 54th Kamiyama High School Culture Fair
has begun!
Whoa!
あ　跳びました
He jumped!
あ　回りました
He spun!
こうしている場合じゃありません
I don't have time for this!
How about trying some calligraphy?
Calligraphy! Calligraphy!
書道　書道
How about trying some calligraphy?
書道　いかがっすかあ
Excuse me?
はい？
You can't grow rice
without land
Chitanda Eru
You can take it if you want.
よかったら　記念にどうぞ
No! I don't have time!
いけません　いけません
From Tsukuba's peak...
つく羽のー
はい
Spring has passed...
春すぎてー
はい
Note that though...
立ち分かれー
はい
Strike at once!
100 Poets Club
Beginners welcome
What do you think?
どうですか
Wanna try?
一戦
For some...
ひさ…
はい
Here, this is yours.
これどうぞ
No! I really don't have time!
いけません　いけません
General Council Office
I finally made it.
やっと着きました
Excuse me!
ごめんください
What a wonderful picture.
素敵な絵
Um...
あのう
えっと　何かご用ですか
Can I help you?
Oh, sorry. I'm looking for the president of the General Council, Tanabe.
すみません
あの　私　総務委員長の田名辺さんに会いに来たんですが
That's me.
僕が田名辺です
Ah, I see!
そうですか
Please give the Classics Club more stall space!
では　古典部の売り場を増やしてください
Global act! Global act!
グローバルアット　グローバルアット
Oh, I'm sorry!
すみません　えっと　私は古典部の部長千反田愛瑠です
I'm the Classics Club's president, Chitanda Eru.
And I have a huge favor to ask of to you.
それでですね　お願いがあるんですが
Please give the Classics Club more stall space!
古典部の売り場を増やしてください
I can't just approve a request out of nowhere like that.
いきなり「増やしてくれ」って言われても　「どうぞ」という訳には
So it's not possible? Thank you.
だめですか　ありがとうございました
No, wait!
いや　待って
That's just our general policy.
それはあくまで原則論でさ
Please tell me your particular circumstances.
何か事情があるなら　話してみてよ
そうですか　ありがとうごぞいます
I see! Thank you very much!
お話をするときは
Wasn't Fukube supposed to be around for this?
福部さんが手伝ってくれるはずだったような
So I prepared to accelerate, and shouted—
で　俺アクセルは踏めるんやったら　行け！
Wait wait wait, that's not gonna cut it!
ちょちょちょ　あかん　あかん
Are you senile or what?
お前あぶないわ
But it works!
なんや
No it doesn't!
事故るよ
というわけなんです
And that's how it is.
That's definitely a tough one.
それは大変だね
I really would like to help,
なんとか手伝ってあげたいけど
but all clubs could cite such circumstances.
事情はどこの部でもあるからね
I can't make an exception just for you.
古典部だけっていうのは
So it's not possible after all...
やっぱりだめですか
I'm sorry.
わるいけど
But...
ああでも　他の部の売り場に古典部の文集を置かせてもらうってことなら
If you wanted to ask other clubs to offer your anthology for sale,
that'd be perfectly fine with us.
こっちは関知しないよ
That's a great idea! We'll definitely consider it!
それはいい方法ですね　考えてみます
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました
Welcome to
the Manga Lab
Good morning!
おはようございます
Morning!
おはよう
Oh, Ibara.
伊原　来たね
You made it.
Kawachi, good morning.
河内先輩　おはようございます
Wow, you even brought a sword?
刀まで用意したんですか
Yeah, though it's just a plastic replica.
ええ　プラスチックの偽物だけど
You should've done the shoes too.
足元も工夫した方がよかったね
So she dressed up after all?
なんだ　結局コスプレしてきてんじゃん
She was totally against it to start with.
あんなに反対してたのに
Should've just listened to Kawachi from the beginning.
河内の言うこと最初から聞いてればよかったんだよ
まあ　そんないい方しなくてもいいじゃん
Come on, don't put it like that.
Ah, good morning!
あ　おはよう
Morning, Yuasa.
おはよう　湯浅
Good morning, President.
おはようございます　部長
Good morning.
おはよう
Did you have to spend much on your outfit?
お金かかちゃった
Just the belt.
ベルト代くらいです
I see.
そう　領収書あったら頂戴ね
Do you have your receipt?
No, don't worry about it.
いえ　大丈夫です
But more importantly, President,
それより　部長
could we—
ここで
Ah...
いえ
Never mind.
なんでもないです
Okay...
そう
Yeah. Sorry.
はい　すみません
やっぱり頼みづらいな　氷菓置いてもらうなんて
It's hard to bring myself to ask if we can sell Hyouka here.
Zeamiz
Hey, who're you dressed as?
ねえねえねえ　これ　何の格好？
Me? Frol.
これ？　フロルだよ
You know, from "They Were Eleven"?
「十一人いる！」って知らない
へえ　私聞いたことないな
I've never heard of that one.
It a really old sci-fi manga.
昔のSF漫画なんだけどね　名作だと思うよ
A real classic, in my opinion.
Could you lend it to me next time?
それ　今度私に貸して
Sure.
うん
What? What are you lending her?
何？　何貸してくれるの？
Manga.
漫画だよ
All right, girls! Let's do this thing!
よし　みんな　気合入れてこう
あのう　もう開いてますか
Excuse me, are you open?
Welcome!
いらっしゃいませ
Everyone! It's our first customer!
お客様第一号でーす
Welcome to
the Manga Lab
いらっしゃいませ
Welcome to
the Manga Lab
Classics Club
Anthology
"Hyouka" issue #46
On sale
Target: Sell all 200!
Sure is quiet.
静かだ
Hooray for shopkeeping.
店番　万歳
Let's see, how many confirmed sales do we have?
とりあえず　確実にはける分は書いておくか
Given the situation, the club members buy two each.
まあ　事情考えて　古典部四名は二部ずつ買うとしよう
With those, and the ones for our advisor and the archive,
それに顧問と保存用で計十二部は確実になくなる
that's twelve right there.
I guess that counts as selling well.
まあ　これだけでもよく出たほうだろう
あれ　誰か俺のアップルジュース知らねえ
Hey, have you seen my apple juice?
Nope.
知らないよ
Damn, I'd barely even taken a sip.
全然飲んでないのに
What's that paper?
なに　その紙
Did something happen?
何かあったか
そんなことよりさ
やべ　眠い
Damn, I'm sleepy.
Um...
あのう
Oh! A punk!
おお！　パンクか！
This guy's a punk, right?
パンクってやつか
Uh, whatcha doing here?
ここ　何やってんっすか
Nothin— I mean, we're selling an anthology.
何も
いえ　文集を売ってます
All of those?
これ全部ですか
Yeah. Long story.
まあ　事情があって
I'll take one.
じゃあ　ひとつください
A customer!
客か　客なのか
A customer? Gotta act friendly!
愛想よくしないと
That'll be 200 yen.
二百円です
I'm not smiling at all.
あ　全然笑えてねえ
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
き　キミ！
Y-You!
はい　何か
What is it?
こ　これ　ちょっと見せてもらえないかな
Could I take a look at that for a moment?
This?
これですか
うん　これだよ　これはいい
This is it!
This is great!
Is it now?
そうですかね
Sorry.
ごめんね
I'm in the Fashion Lab.
僕　被服研なんだけどね
We're doing a fashion show,
ファッションショーをやるんだけど
but I forgot to bring something to use as a formal pocket accessory.
フォーマル系の胸ポケットに合わせるもの忘れてたんだよ
This is really wonderful!
実にいいよ　これは
You can have it.
あげますよ
Seriously? Can I really?
本当！　マジくれんの？
It's basically trash anyway, so feel free.
どうせゴミですんで　どうぞ
Then have this.
じゃあ　これあげるよ
That's the winning number for our show,
それ　うちのショーの優先券になってるから
Fashion Lab
so if you bring that to our changing room,
それ持って被服室にきてくれれば
最高のコーディネートさせてもらうよ
we'll get you into the spotlight!
Thanks...
This would be more Satoshi's style.
行くとしたら　里志くらいだな
いや　あいつにはあいつのこだわりがあるか
Actually, I think his style is a little beyond me.
So much for that.
いらない
ま　とりあえず一冊は売れたな
But at least I managed to sell a copy.
上を向いて歩こう
涙が零れないように
思い出す　春の日
Oops, I did it again!
またです
一人ぼっちの夜
Hey, you!
ねえ　あなた
Yes?
はい？
Taking keepsake
photos!
Photography Club
幸せは
How about a picture?
写真とかどうかしら
No, this won't do!
いけません　いけません　いけません
I can't do my job if I keep getting sidetracked by anything interesting!
興味を惹かれるたびに立ち止まっていたのでは
ちっとも役割が果たせないじゃないですか
Occult Seekers! We're the Occult Seekers!
オカルト研　オカルト研です
Wanna watch UFOs together?
一緒にUFO呼びませんか
We have ghost photos as well!
心霊写真の展示もやってます
The Enterprise is on exhibit!
エンタープライズを展示中でーす
The launching ceremony starts soon!
でも　これから進水式を行いまーす
Global act!
グローバルアット
Want a charm?
おまじないいかがっすか
前しか見えなくなるメガネがどこかに落ちてないものでしょうか
Hasn't anyone invented glasses that only let you look straight ahead?
状況は非科学的に 感情のモンタージュ
The situation is unscientific
A montage of emotions
誰が誰を呼んでる
Who's calling who?
振り向けば逃げてく視線（感じる）
You look away when our eyes are about to meet
I can feel it
気のせいじゃつれないよ アンテナは才能って言うでしょ
Am I just imagining things? It's so cold of you
It takes talent to read minds
だって（だって） 知りたい（君は違うの？）
You know
I wanna know
Don't you?
青春の温度差 今のうち正してあげるよ
I'll fix the fire of youth in your heart while I can
明日解決するなら 今でもよくない？
If we can do it today why leave it for tomorrow
君のミステリー解いてみたい
I want to solve your mystery
少年の秘密めいた背中探せ（今日も）
Look for the back of the boy, burdened with secrets
Even today
君はファンタジー 惹かれてゆくよ（ずるい）
You are a fantasy and I'm drawn to you
This growing curiosity
膨らんだ好奇心 とりたくはないのに
There's no twist in the story
気になるよ 興味深い どうして
I can't stop thinking about it
It's so interesting
But why?
Quiz Trial
Next time: Dead at Dusk.
次回　夕べには骸に
Dead at Dusk